FAHID MOHAMMED

I have been developing software systems since I was a teenager. So far I have worked in academia, as a freelancer and within the industry as a developer and/or educator. My research at the university of Bath looks into transparency in AI (multi-agent systems), where I investigate how to communicate the justification for agent behaviour.

From working in various environments and amongst individuals of different backgrounds, I have developed good communication skills and the ability to effectively discuss technical subjects with a non-technical audience and vice-versa. Over the years, I have developed and deployed systems ranging from embedded systems to micro-services. Below I provide a glimpse of my experience so far. Additionally, I have pet-projects, one of which was the National Nominee for the m-Govt & Participation Category of World Summit Award Mobile 2014.

EXPERIENCE

ENGINEER, HAEMA.CO; REMOTE - 2023-2024

As part of the founding team, I Lead the development of the iOS app from concept to initial beta (prefunding). Designed the architecture of several backend services and lead the public beta testing programme.

AI DEVELOPER & DESIGNER, YOKERU; REMOTE, UK - 2023-2024

Developed new features and maintained the core product. Worked closely with stakeholders to improve the reliability of the platform. Worked closely with clients to better understand how they use the platform and to improve the product in a way that best meets their various needs.

> CASUAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, SYNKD; REMOTE, UK - 2022-2023 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, EHEALTH; NG - 2017-2018 SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, ECNX; UK - 2016-2017

Worked as part of a team (both co-located and remote) to implement (from scratch), update and maintain several software systems. In most cases, the systems handled large volumes of data and required high availability. See: https://www.ehealthafrica.org/lomis-case-study

> TEACHING ASSISTANT, UNIVERSITY OF BATH; BATH, UK - 2018-2024 TEACHING ASSISTANT, JAIN ONLINE; REMOTE, INDIA – 2023 TUTOR, CAPITA; REMOTE, UK - 2022-2023 INSTRUCTOR, CODE FIRST GIRLS; REMOTE, UK - 2022

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INSTRUCTOR, SKILLS-UNION; REMOTE, UK - 2021-2021

Designed course contents (Jain Online) and delivered live remote classes (Code First Girls, Jain Online, Skills-Union) on Application development using Python, Back-end software development (NodeJS), Data structures and algorithms, Front-end software development (React), & Data Analysis and Visualisation (Python). At the University of Bath, I taught the lab (hands-on practical aspects) sessions of Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Intelligent-Agents, Intelligent Control & Cognitive Systems, Principles of Programming & Software Engineering units to masters and undergraduate students. Assessed NCFE Levels 2-4 coding submission and provided learners with formative & summative feedback (Capita).

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK - PHD COMPUTER SCIENCE, [AWAITING OUTCOME] UNIVERSITY OF BATH, UK - MSC SOFTWARE SYSTEMS, 2015 (MERIT)

SKILLS

Databases / Db Infrastructure: CouchDB, Firebase, MongoBB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, PouchDB, SQLite, Supabase.

Frameworks: AngularJS, Bubble.io, Dash, Django, Electron, ExpressJS / NodeJS, iOS Development with SwiftUI, LangChain, React, ReactNative.

Languages: C, C#, GraphQL, HTML, Java, JavaScript, Python, Swift, SQL, TypeScript, VB.NET.

Tech Stack: APIs, Agile Development (Kanban, Scrum), AWS (also Digital Ocean, Heroku & Modal), CI/CD (TravisCl, Xcode Cloud), Docker, Git / GitHub, Jira, Kubernetes, TestFlight.